<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Landscape Fire and Resource Management Planning Tools (LANDFIRE)</origin>
        <origin>Earth Resources Observation and Science Center (EROS)</origin>
        <origin>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</origin>
        <origin>Timothy Hatten, USGS PM</origin>
        <pubdate>20230501</pubdate>
        <title>LANDFIRE 2022 Existing Vegetation Height (EVH) CONUS </title>
        <edition>LF 2022</edition>
        <geoform>raster digital data</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Sioux Falls, SD</pubplace>
          <publish>Earth Resources Observation and Science Center (EROS), U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://www.landfire.gov</onlink>
        <onlink>https://doi.org/10.5066/P974JF8W</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>LANDFIRE's (LF) 2022 update (LF 2022) Existing Vegetation Height (EVH) represents the average height of the dominant vegetation for a 30-m cell. EVH is produced separately for tree, shrub, and herbaceous lifeforms using training data depicting the weighted average height by species cover and Existing Vegetation Type (EVT) lifeform. Decision tree models using field reference data, lidar, and Landsat are developed separately for each lifeform, then lifeform specific height class layers are merged along with land cover into a single EVH product based on the dominant lifeform of each pixel. EVH ranges are continuous for the herbaceous lifeform category ranging from 0.1 to 1 meter with decimeter increments, 0.1 to 3 meters for shrub lifeform, and 1 to 99 meters for tree lifeform. If the height values of each lifeform exceed the continuous value range, they are binned into the appropriate maximum height class. EVH is then reconciled through QA/QC measures to ensure lifeform is synchronized with Existing Vegetation Cover (EVC). Urban and developed areas are derived from the National Land Cover Database (NLCD), and the latest available Microsoft Building Footprint dataset. Agricultural lands originate from the 2022 Cropland Data Layer (CDL) and the 2019 California Statewide Crop Mapping layer. Disturbance events after 2016 are accounted for by incorporating transition rulesets using LF 2022 Fuel Disturbance (FDist). LF uses EVH as an input for LF 2022 Fuel Vegetation Height (FVH). </abstract>
      <purpose>The LANDFIRE 2022 Update (LF 2022) is designed to produce vegetation, disturbance, and fuels products that inform wildland fire and ecological decision systems. LF 2022 is another update to the LF 2016 Remap base map and LF 2020, it includes adjustments to vegetation and fuels in disturbed areas for disturbances recorded in 2021 and 2022. Disturbances in 2022 represent the first full fiscal year of disturbance. Transition rulesets for vegetation account for disturbances from 2017 to 2022 while fuel updates utilize 2012 to 2022 disturbances. In LF 2022 Existing Vegetation Type (EVT) Ecological Systems classifications are the same as LF 2020, except in areas where agriculture or urban areas have changed. LF 2022 contains the first application of the "zero to one" Time Since Disturbance (TSD) rules for EVC and EVH transition rules. Both LF Existing Vegetation Cover (EVC) and Height (EVH), as well as all fuels products, are 2023 capable in disturbed areas. 

LF 2022 products are designed to facilitate national and regional level strategic fire and resource management planning and reporting of management activities. The principal purposes of the products include providing, 1) national level, landscape scale geospatial products to support fire and fuels management planning, and 2) consistent fuels products to support fire planning, analysis, and budgeting to evaluate fire management alternatives.  

Products are created at a 30 meter raster; however, the applicability of products varies by location and specific use. LF products were designed to support 1) national (all states) strategic planning, 2) regional (single large states or groups of smaller states), and 3) strategic/tactical planning for large sub regional landscapes and Fire Management Units (FMUs) (such as significant portions of states or multiple federal administrative entities). The applicability of LF products to support fire and land management planning on smaller areas will vary by product, location, and specific use. Managers and planners must evaluate LF products according to the scale and requirements specific to their needs. </purpose>
      <supplinf>Beginning in the LF 2020 update and continued into the LF 2022 update, all CONUS products are created with a 90km buffer into both Canada and Mexico. The data in this buffer was last updated in LF 2020. LF 2022 AK products also feature a 90km buffer into Canada, but this buffer was last updated with new data in LF 2016 Remap. The following LF 2022 products have 2023 capability functionality: EVH, EVC, CBD, CBH, CC, CH, F13, F40, FVC, FVH, FVT, CFFDRS and FDist.

</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>2022</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>ground condition</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Annually </update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-78.9660</westbc>
        <eastbc>-78.7462</eastbc>
        <northbc>36.1895</northbc>
        <southbc>35.8223</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
        <themekey>biota</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>USGS Thesaurus</themekt>
        <themekey>fires</themekey>
        <themekey>hazard preparedness</themekey>
        <themekey>remote sensing</themekey>
        <themekey>image collections</themekey>
        <themekey>geospatial datasets</themekey>
        <themekey>geographic information systems</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>raster digital data </themekey>
        <themekey>Existing Vegetation Height</themekey>
        <themekey>EVH</themekey>
        <themekey>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</themekey>
        <themekey>U.S. Forest Service (USFS)</themekey>
        <themekey>LANDFIRE 2022</themekey>
        <themekey>LF 2022</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt>
        <placekey>US</placekey>
        <placekey>CONUS</placekey>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekey>Continental U.S.</placekey>
        <placekey>Conterminous United States</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>None </useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>LANDFIRE, Earth Resources Observation and Science Center (EROS), U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Service Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>physical</addrtype>
          <address>47914 252nd Street</address>
          <city>Sioux Falls</city>
          <state>SD</state>
          <postal>57198</postal>
          <country>U.S.</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>605-594-6151</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>helpdesk@landfire.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>These products were created by the LF team at USGS EROS, Sioux Falls, SD. Refer to the contact information throughout this metadata to contact the LF team.</datacred>
    <secinfo>
<secsys>None in place</secsys>
<secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
<sechandl>If there is ever doubt, contact the LF Help Desk at helpdesk@landfire.gov</sechandl>
</secinfo>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 10; ESRI ArcCatalog 10.7.1</native>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>USGS Advanced Research Computing (ARC)</origin>
        <pubdate>2021</pubdate>
        <title>USGS Denali Supercomputer: U.S. Geological Survey</title>
        <geoform>publication</geoform>
        <onlink>https://www.usgs.gov/advanced-research-computing/usgs-denali-supercomputer</onlink>
        <onlink>https://www.usgs.gov/advanced-research-computing</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Products were tested to ensure that each attribute is represented consistently across all data sets. Attributes were not validated against in person observations. </attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>The products were pixel "truth" tested for consistency of land or water characteristics across all products. </logic>
    <complete>Products were formally tested to ensure that valid data was produced for all pixels. Each product was then validated and tested for duplicates, omissions, and errors.</complete>
    <lineage>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>Beginning with the new base map of LF 2016 Remap (LF Remap), products were created using recent advances in image compositing, tiling algorithms, and faster computing hardware to ensure that LF products remained relevant. LF Remap leveraged the Landsat archive, lidar data, and user contributed field plot data compiled into the LF Reference Database (LFRDB), to create new vegetation products.  

Reference resources included, but were not limited to, Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) program plot data (USFS https://fia.fs.fed.us/), Landsat Dynamic Surface Water Extent [(DSWE) USGS https://www.usgs.gov/landsat-missions], the National Land Cover Database [(NLCD) USGS https://www.mrlc.gov/data], and National Agricultural Statistics Service [(NASS) USDA - https://www.nass.usda.gov/].  

For LF 2022 reference resources included, but were not limited to, Monitoring Trends in Burn Severity [(MTBS) USGS https://mtbs.gov/], Burned Area Reflectance Classification [(BARC) USFS and USGS] and Rapid Assessment of Vegetation Condition after Wildfire [(RAVG) https://burnseverity.cr.usgs.gov/ravg/], National Agricultural Statistics Service [(NASS) USDA - https://www.nass.usda.gov/] for 2022, PAD 3.0 for federal and protected lands identification [https://doi.org/10.5066/P9Q9LQ4B], and a rasterized version of the Microsoft building footprint for 2022 to update developed areas [https://github.com/Microsoft/USBuildingFootprints]. Disturbances in LF 2022 were also identified with LF's remote sensing of landscape change (RSLC), which identifies spectral change in vegetation using automated algorithms and image analyst review of the entire country with Landsat imagery. Burned Area (BA) data from Landsat was also used and national events (polygons) were used to identify areas and types of disturbance. 

To read more about LF reference resources go to https://www.landfire.gov/reference.php. Information about LF 2022 product testing is available by request or via the website at https://www.landfire.gov.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20230501</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Raster</direct>
    <rastinfo>
      <rasttype>Grid Cell</rasttype>
      <rowcount>20729</rowcount>
      <colcount>24853</colcount>
    </rastinfo>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>Albers Conical Equal Area</mapprojn>
          <albers>
            <stdparll>29.5</stdparll>
            <stdparll>45.5</stdparll>
            <longcm>-96.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>23.0</latprjo>
            <feast>0</feast>
            <fnorth>0</fnorth>
          </albers>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>row and column</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>30</absres>
            <ordres>30</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meters</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983 (NAD 83)</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef />
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>EVH</enttypl>
        <enttypd>LF 2022 EVH attributes spreadsheet.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>LF 2022</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>VALUE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Value representing height (m).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>-9999</edomv>
            <edomvd>NoData</edomvd>
            <edomvds>LF 2022</edomvds>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
        <attrdomv>
          <rdom>
            <rdommin>11</rdommin>
            <rdommax>310</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLASSNAMES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Existing Vegetation Height. Tree, shrub, and herb height values 101 to 310.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><udom>101 to 199 - Tree heights 1 meter to 99 meters or greater.
201 to 230 - Shrub heights - 1 meter to 3 meters or greater.
301 to 310 - Herb heights - 0.1 meter to 1 meter or greater.
</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>R</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Red color value/255</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>255</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>G</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Green color value/255</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>255</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>B</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Blue color value/255</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>255</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>RED</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Red color value. </attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>0.0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1.0</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GREEN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Green color value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>0.0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1.0</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BLUE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Blue color value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>LF 2022</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv><rdom>
            <rdommin>0.0</rdommin>
            <rdommax>1.0</rdommax>
          </rdom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>LANDFIRE (LF) 2022 Existing Vegetation Height (EVH) CONUS. An Attribute Table is included with each product download as a .csv and embedded in the metadata. The  Attribute Data Dictionary (ADD) can be found at https://www.landfire.gov/.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>https://www.landfire.gov/evh.php</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
          <cntper>GS ScienceBase</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
          <address>Denver Federal Center, Building 810, Mail Stop 302</address>
          <city>Denver</city>
          <state>CO</state>
          <postal>80225</postal>
          <country>United States</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-888-275-8747</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>sciencebase@usgs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>This product is reproduced from geospatial information prepared by the U.S. Department of the Interior (DOI) USGS EROS. By removing the contents of this package or taking receipt of these files via electronic file transfer methods, you understand that the data stored on this media can be updated at any time. Represented features may not be in an accurate geographic location. USGS EROS makes no expressed or implied warranty, including warranty of merchantability and fitness, with respect to the character, function, or capabilities of the data or their appropriateness for any user's purposes. USGS EROS reserves the right to correct, update, modify, or replace this geospatial information without notification.

Unless otherwise stated, all data, metadata and related materials are considered to satisfy the quality standards relative to the purpose for which the data were collected. Although these data and associated metadata have been reviewed for accuracy and completeness and approved for release by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the display or utility of the data for other purposes, nor on all computer systems, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform><digtinfo>
<formname>ARCG</formname>
<formverd>20230501</formverd> 
<formspec>LF 2022</formspec>
</digtinfo>
<digtopt><onlinopt><computer><networka><networkr>https://doi.org/10.5066/P974JF8W</networkr></networka></computer></onlinopt></digtopt></digform>
      <fees>none</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20230501</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>LANDFIRE, Earth Resources Observation and Science Center (EROS), U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Customer Service Representative</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>physical</addrtype>
          <address>47914 252nd Street</address>
          <city>Sioux Falls</city>
          <state>SD</state>
          <postal>57198</postal>
          <country>U.S.</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>605-594-6151</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>helpdesk@landfire.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metsi>
<metscs>None</metscs>
<metsc>Unclassified</metsc>
<metshd>None</metshd>
</metsi>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>